So one of the most common questions that I get asked
when I show the demo of agentic AI application
is that it does not generate anything.
So how can this be a generative AI application?
And the answer to that question is
that agentic AI is not generative AI.
They are both different.
And sometimes the reason why people confuse
between generative AI and agentic AI
is that they both use a large language model.
But that's probably the only similarity between the two.
Now let's go and take a look
at what's the difference between generative and agentic AI.
Now let's start with what is a focus of both.
For generative AI, the focus is on content generation.
So whether you want to generate text,
images, code, you will use generative AI.
But the focus area for agentic AI is to execute
complex tasks autonomously with minimal human intervention.
Now let's try and understand this through a use case.
So let's say you have a human developer
and you want to improve his productivity.
So what you will do is you will build a generative AI application
such as a code generator through which
it can generate code from a natural language query.
Now let's assume there's a production defect
and he analyzes the issue and then pulls a query
to the generative AI app to generate some code for it
so that you can fix the defect.
So it will generate the code.
You will implement the code at test the code
and then it will be good.
So it has improves his productivity.
Now let's take the same use case on how it will be implemented
through the agentic AI.
So here you will build a developer agent
and you will not require human intervention.
Or at least you will require minimal human intervention.
So what this developer agent will do is
so it will evaluate the logs
and understand what the defect is.
Then based on the evaluation of the logs,
it will generate code.
It will update the code, test it out and implement it.
So it will do everything by itself
and would not require the human intervention.
Maybe you can keep the human in loop at the end.
Once the code has been generated, update it, test it.
Then just before the implementation,
you can have a human in loop who will review
and then implement.
Next, generative AI can also act as a productivity enhancer.
So maybe you will have a generative AI application
that can do the content creation
such as press briefings, creation of videos,
brochures for the marketing team.
On the other hand, for agentic AI,
a great use case would be a customer service chatbot
that can answer the complex user queries
by understanding the user queries
and then retrieving the relevant data
from relational, non-relational, or ragged-based solutions
and give a response back to the end user.
Now let's take a look at the capabilities
and limitation of generative and agentic AI.
So the problem is the only similarity between generative
and agentic AI is that they are both powered
by a large language model.
So you could have clawed, lamothree, open AI,
or any other LLM.
Next, generative AI is limited to the training data
of the LLM.
So whatever data the LLM has been trained on,
it can answer questions only related to its training data.
It also does not have access to real-time data
or enterprise data.
So let's say for LLM,
the training was completed on June 2023.
So any event happening after that date,
the LLM would not be able to answer those questions.
So it cannot also tell you, what is the weather like today
in New York?
Because it has no access to real-time or enterprise data.
On the other hand, agentic AI can integrate with enterprise
data sources, relational, non-relational, vector DB.
It can also access real-time data
such as weather data, hotel booking, flight booking,
because it can integrate with tools
that can make an API call to the backend systems
and get you the real-time or enterprise data.
Then large language models are stateless.
They have no memory.
So you can enable memory in a generative applications,
maybe through LinkedIn where you can enable conversation,
buffer memory, but by default, it does not have any memory.
While as in the agentic AI,
you will have a long-term and short-term memory
to contextualize and personalize the response
to the user.
Genity AI also does not have any reasoning capability
through which it can break down the user request
into multiple tasks.
Well, as that capability is available with the agentic AI
where it will evaluate the user request
and break it down into smaller, subtask
using the large language model.
Now let's go ahead and take a look at a common architecture
for Genity AI-based application.
So we'll have a front end through which the user would send
his queries, then maybe you will have a rest API,
maybe a Lambda function, and then Amazon bedrock
and some underlying foundational model.
Now in case of agentic AI,
you will have a large language model
that will be driving the agent.
Then it will have some tools.
Let's say Lambda function, maybe knowledge bases,
which will query the backend systems
and get the data for the HR agent.
It will have a memory to contextualize and personalize
the responses.
It will have some guardrails.
Then if you're also building multi agent applications,
you will need orchestration framework,
such as Amazon bedrock multi agent orchestration framework,
land graph, crew AI, and so on.
So how would a typical Genity AI application work?
So let's say you have a user who's doing to generate
some content, he will send that request or prompt
via AWS API gateway to a Lambda function.
And then this Lambda function is going to enhance
the user input with a prompt template.
And then send that request to Amazon bedrock
and Amazon bedrock will further send that request
to a foundation model, then it will generate a response
and send it back to the user.
So in case of agentic application, how would that work?
So you will have a user that will send that request
to an agent, then agent is going to break down
the user task into multiple steps.
And then it will use the tools that it has
maybe a Lambda function, maybe a better
on knowledge base to retrieve the data from the backend.
And once it gets a response back from these backend systems,
it's going to consolidate that input
and send it back to the user.
So this is some key differences between
generative and agentic AI. I hope you like this lecture. Thank you.